うまくいったのね
So it went well?
Yeah.
殺したの？
Did you kill her?
執行官がね
An Enforcer did.
Does it hurt to know she's dead?
心が痛む？
I don't know...
分からない
でも　少し悲しい
But I feel a little sad.
ちゃんと　教えた用量を守ってるね
Looks like you've been following
my dosage instructions.
色相を見てみようか
Why don't I check your Hue?
奇麗だ
It's clear.
効かないっていわれてた薬を少し飲んだだけで
To think that just taking a bit of that medicine
made me feel so much better
こんなにも楽になれるなんて
even though they said
it wasn't effective...
人には固有の処方がある
Prescriptions should be
unique to each individual.
それを無視して　ただ　強い薬を飲ませるのは
Ignoring that fact and prescribing strong medicine
is the same as using violence.
暴力を振るっているのと同じだ
どうして　私をクリアにしてくれるの？
Why are you helping me
become clear?
君自身の意志が欲しいからだよ
Because I want you
to have your own will.
私の意志？
My own will?
Yeah.
僕のそばにいてくれ
Stay by my side.
私　何でもする
I'll do anything.
ありがとう
Thank you.
シビュラよ　お前を裁くまで　あともう少しだ
Sibyl...
It won't be long before
I bring you to justice.
私は　裏口を調べてきます
I'll go check the back door.
了解
Okay.
「犯罪係数　２６」
Crime Coefficient is 26.
Inspector registered at CID.
「刑事課登録　監視官」
「警告　執行官による　反逆行為は記録の上　本部に報告されます」
Warning. Any rebellious conduct
by Enforcers will be recorded
and reported to headquarters.
奇麗なものだ
How clear...
何なの　あいつ
What's with him?
奪われ続けるなら
If I keep having things taken away from me, I'm gonna lose my mind
Ubaware tsuzukeru nara mou kurutte shimau yo
奪われ続けるなら
もう狂ってしまうよ
This endless "end" will make me stop breathing
Owari no nai "owari" ni boku wa iki wo shinaku natte
終わりの無い「終わり」に僕は息をしなくなって
Enigmatic Feeling
Enigmatic feeling
Why do they have to take things away from me? I'm about to fall apart
Ubawanakya ikenai no? Mou hodokete shimau yo
奪わなきゃいけないの
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
The world began to melt
Sekai ga tokedashite
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
God descended to confront and ask me
Kami-sama ga orite kite boku ni tsukitsuketa
神様が降りて来て
僕に突きつけた
"Who are you?"
Who are you?
I freed myself by walking in the divide of this world broken into two
Futatsu ni wakareta sekai ni sotte jibun wo hanatta
２つに分かれた世界に沿って
自分を放った
Is there only one God in such a fine borderline?
Kamihitoe darou kamihitoe darou kyoukaisen kami wa hitori na no?
紙一重だろう　紙一重だろう
境界線　神は１人なの
I'm gonna lose my mind, I'm gonna lose my mind...
Okashiku natte okashiku natte
おかしくなって おかしくなって
Suddenly I'll find myself taking you away
Fui ni kimi wo ubatte shimau no darou
ふいに君を奪ってしまうのだろう
Crazy! Crazy!
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
Because my heart can't focus
Pinto no awanai kokoro ni
ピントの合わない心に
Shake me! Shake me!
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I can't even look into the mirror
Kagami sae mo nozokenai
鏡さえも覗けない
#5: Unforbidden Games
Impressive as usual.
Already finished reading the case files?
さすがですね
事件の資料　もう読み終わったんですか
You're the one
who's impressive.
さすがなのは　お前さんの方だろ
Hm?
It's only been a day since
that truly terrible incident happened.
あれだけの事件が　起きてから　たった一晩だ
And yet, you're so calm...
なのに　お前さんの落ち着きようときたら…
Are you really a human?
ホントに人間か
That doesn't sound nice.
人聞きが悪いです
I'd be lying if I said
it didn't shock me.
ショックじゃないって言ったら　嘘になります
But even more than that,
it makes me feel that I must work harder.
でも　それ以上に　やらなきゃって気持ちの方が強いんです
I see...
そうか
Sorry, but I'll come
straight to the point.
早速で悪いんですが
I'd like to ask you to interrogate
Representative Masuda.
先生には　増田代議士の聴取をお願いします
A representative, huh?
代議士先生か
Kotoku Masuda
He's calm now, right?
今はもう落ち着いているんだろ？
Yes...
はい　不自然なほどに
...unnaturally so.
He may be part of a trap...
やつの存在自体が　トラップの可能性
That's what you're thinking, huh?
そこに　思い至っているわけだ
By analyzing the logs,
ログの解析により
we succeeded in identifying
the place we think Kamui is hiding.
鹿矛囲が潜伏していると思われる場所の特定には　成功しています
We've already sent
in Drones, but...
すでに　ドローンを　向かわせていますが…
You'll probably end up
going yourself after all.
結局　直接　出向く羽目になるだろうな
Inspector Shisui, who called
Ms. Aoyanagi to the scene...
青柳さんを呼び出した　酒々井監視官…
There was no mistake that
the voice on the phone was indeed hers.
音声は　本人のもので　間違いなかったようです
Kamui's someone who can
win over an Inspector.
監視官を懐柔するような相手が
There's no way that
he'd let us easily get something on him.
簡単に　尻尾をつかませてくれるはずがない
So you think Kamui's that good.
買っているわけだ　鹿矛囲を
I do think that
we should be on guard.
警戒は　すべきだと思っています
In fact, we couldn't
detect his Psycho-Pass
実際　昨日も
despite the fact that he must've been
at the crime scene yesterday.
現場にいたはずの鹿矛囲のサイコパスはつかめなかった
Is that causing you
to remember...
思い出しているのか
Shogo Makishima?
槙島聖護を
似たような不気味さは　感じているのかもしれません
I might be feeling
a similar kind of creepiness.
But something
is definitely different.
でも　何かが決定的に違う
If we can figure out
what that something is,
その何かが分かれば
we'll probably be able to get closer
to Kamui's true character, huh?
鹿矛囲の正体に　大きく近づけるんだろうな
That's one of the reasons
I came to you.
だから　先生とお話ししているというのもあります
Sorry, but I'm not a magician.
残念だが　俺は手品師じゃない
I can't pull on a string
and change it into flowers.
糸くず　引っ張って　花に変えてやることはできんよ
You're just being modest.
ご謙遜を
Are you leaving?
行くのか
はい
Yes.
Be very careful.
じゅうぶん　注意しろよ
We'll be joined by Division 3
for the investigation.
捜査は三係と共同で行います
That should be
enough firepower.
戦力的には　十二分でしょう
I'm surprised the Chief
is going along with this.
よく　局長が許可したもんだ
Well... she probably isn't
keen on the strategy itself,
いや　作戦自体には後ろ向きだが
but she must've decided
the best route was to hedge her bets.
行う以上は　リスクヘッジすべきという判断か
Really, you're amazing.
ホント　さすがです
I do understand that there's no
validity whatsoever in her actions.
理解しているさ
彼女の行動には何ら正当性はない
But it's easier to handle her
by leaving her in the chain of command
しかし　単独で動かれるよりは
命令系統の下に置いた方が　まだ御しやすい
rather than allowing her
to act on her own.
In any event, our losses so far aren't
big enough to warrant taking action...
いずれにしても　現状の損害は問題にすべきほどではない
...though it will take some time
to replace the Inspectors we lost.
損失した監視官の補充には　多少の時間が必要だろうが
As for the surplus Enforcers,
if we put them with other Inspectors,
余剰の執行官は　別の監視官につければ
we can keep them working.
遊ばせておくことにはなるまい
I'm Kaede Hasuike.
I've been transferred to Division 1 starting today.
本日付で　一係に転属になりました
蓮池楓です
What a warm welcome.
手厚い歓迎だ
I heard that you got
transferred to Division 1.
一係に異動になったそうだな
Yes.
はい
You and Inspector Aoyanagi...
青柳監視官は　あなたの同期で友人だった
...started working here
in the same year and were friends...
She was also your boss.
お前の上司でもあった
I...
自分は…
You performed enforcement
on a latent criminal, that's all.
お前は潜在犯を執行しただけだ
You did nothing wrong.
何も間違ったことはしていない
But...!
しかし…
Just...
ただ…　しばらく　俺の前に顔は見せないでくれ
...don't appear in front
of me for a while.
I'm scared...
怖いんです
I saw such a terrible thing
happen right before my eyes...
あんなことがあって　間近で見ちゃって
I want to tell myself that
this won't change me, but...
自分が変わらずにいられるって　自信が欲しい
Ms. Kunizuka...
六合塚さん…
It's okay. Even Inspectors
have the right to cry.
いいのよ
監視官にだって　泣く権利はある
Yes...
はい
Yayoi...
弥生さん
What is it?
何？
Enforcer Sakuya Togane...
What do you think of him?
東金朔夜執行官のこと　どう思いますか
I think he's an excellent Enforcer
with outstanding judgment and performance.
判断力と実行力に優れた　優秀な執行官だと思うけど
Yes...
そうですね
I see. So I'm in charge
of this case, huh?
なるほど
この件に関しての担当者は　私というわけ
But no matter how much you blame me,
I can't take responsibility for it...
しかし　どんなに責められても私には責任の取りようがない
...because we can't
change the past.
過去を覆すことなんてできないのだから
Let's just do our best to make use
of that which was brought to life...
生まれてしまったものは　せいぜい　活用しましょう
...in order that we may evolve.
われわれの進化のために
Besides, aren't you curious...
それに　気にならない？
...about how she gets
affected by "that"?
彼女があれに　どんな影響を受けるのか
We'll be arriving there soon.
間もなく到着します
It's a place where they conduct
Military Drone experiments.
現場は　軍事ドローンの実験場です
Our purpose
is strictly investigation.
目的は　あくまで調査ですが
However, equipment with risk level B
is permitted as a precautionary measure.
万一の場合に備えて　危険度Ｂレベルの装備を許可
Also, this operation is being carried out
by Division 1 and Division 3 together.
また　本作戦は一係と三係が　共同で行うものとします
Enforcers are expected
to consider the situation
執行官各自は　担当監視官にこだわることなく
and follow any appropriate instructions,
regardless of who your lead Inspector is.
状況を鑑みて　適切と思われる指示に従ってください
I never thought
I'd come back here...
まさか　ここに戻ることになるとは…
Inspector Tsunemori, is there a point
in taking so many people with you?
先輩　そんな　大所帯で行く意味　あるんですか？
The personnel assignment
was given by the Chief.
人員配置に関しては　局長の指示よ
The interrogation
of Representative Masuda...
増田代議士の聴取
The analysis
of the barricade incident site...
立てこもり現場の解析
And, the Holo analysis
you requested...
それから　先輩が依頼した　ホロの解析作業まで
We've got so much to do that
we're about to explode here.
こっちも　やること多過ぎて　パンクしますよ
I gave everyone tasks that
I determined they could handle.
それぞれ　作業を割り振ってある
じゅうぶんにこなせると　判断しました
I'm saying that it may be
too much to handle.
負担が　重過ぎるんじゃないかって話です
Besides, Drones have already
investigated that site, right?
第一　その現場は　すでにドローンが調査済みなんですよね
There are things that we can only learn
by actually visiting the place.
実際に　行ってみないと　分からないこともある
That way of thinking
is out of date.
時代遅れです　そういうの
It's not necessarily true that new ideas
and approaches are always right.
進んだ時代が　常に正しいとは限らない
We've arrived at the site.
I'm going to hang up.
現場に到着　切ります
Inspector Shimotsuki.
霜月監視官
The Ministry of Welfare
has instructed us
増田代議士について
色相が改善に向かっていることを理由に
to release Representative Masuda
because his Hue is improving.
釈放を求める通達が　厚生省から届きました
What?
No matter how you look at it,
someone's putting pressure on us.
圧力ですね　どう考えても
Japanese society has always been held up
by the vitality of its citizens.
日本の社会を　支えているのは
いつの時代も　国民の活力なのです
We can't refuse
the Ministry of Welfare's orders.
厚生省からの通達を　突っぱねるわけにはいかないし
And, I have been stressing that
to maintain that vitality,
Even if we can play dumb,
we can probably buy just a day or two at most.
あれや　これやと　ごまかせても
what we need more than anything
is to provide security and well-being.
せいぜい　１日か２日でしょうね
This place used to be
a trading port.
もともと　貿易港だったこの場所は
After the port was closed,
it was used as an unmanned warehouse.
破棄されて以来　無人倉庫として使われていた
Then, the Ministry
of National Defense's
そこに目を付けたのが
Military Drones Research
and Development division started eyeing it.
国防省の軍事ドローン　研究開発部門
There's enough space
to store parts and equipment,
ドローン自体は　もとより
備品や装備を　保管しておく場所に困らず
not to mention
the Drones themselves.
In addition, it's unmanned,
so accidents are unlikely.
それに　無人なので　事故も起こりづらい
There's no better place for conducting
Military Drone activation experiments.
軍事用ドローンの起動実験にこれほど適した場所は　ありませんよ
I see...
なるほど
Whoa!
Next is the experiment on synching
information between two Drones.
次はドローン２機を使った情報連結の実験を
Sugo? Is that you?
須郷　須郷か
It's been a while!
久しぶりじゃないか
I guess I haven't seen you
since you went to the facility.
お前が施設行きになって以来か
When did you come back?
いつ戻ってきたんだ？
It's not that I came back.
戻ってはいない
What?
I am an Enforcer
at the MWPSB.
今は公安の執行官だ
O-Oh... I see.
そうだったのか
Well then, see you later.
邪魔したな
I'm going back to my post.
持ち場に戻る
I see, this is a place
he used to work at.
なるほど　彼の古巣か
Nothing unusual, huh?
異常はなしか
Can't we just stand by for orders?
もう待機でいいんじゃないですか
Why don't we leave the rest to Division 1,
since they're so hung about this?
後はやる気満々の一係さんに任せておきましょうよ
Chief Kasei's favorite, huh?
禾生局長のお気に入りか
Being forced to work with her
is such a pain in the ass, isn't it...?
付き合わされる方は　たまったものじゃないな
Only authorized people
are allowed to enter this area
「関係者以外立ち入り禁止で人が住んでいる可能性はない」
and there's no possibility
that anyone lives here.
That's what that
chief operator said, isn't it?
そう言ってましたね　あの主任オペレーターは
そうね　スタッフ以外の記録は残っていない
Yeah. There's no record
of anyone else besides the staff.
But... cymatic scans
are meaningless to a ghost.
でも　透明人間にサイマティックスキャンは意味がない
On the contrary, what he needs
to be careful about are human eyes.
逆に注意すべきは人間の目
A place where scanners
are installed and is also deserted...
スキャナーが配備された上で　人通りのほとんどない場所
Dead end...
行き止まり…
Mr. Togane?
東金さん？
The building on the left hand side
has emergency exits facing the street.
左側のビル
非常口を正面に設けた設計が成されている
Then it's unnatural that the building
next to it has nothing but a wall.
ならば…
裏側に当たるこのスペースが　壁で区切られているのは不自然だ
A structurally unnecessary wall...
構造上不必要な壁
It's within the range
of cymatic scans' monitoring...
サイマティックスキャンによる監視範囲内
And, it's the deepest end
of a deserted path.
そして人通りの少ない通路の最深部という立地
It's a Holo...
ホロ…
This is what you'd called
detective's intuition.
刑事の勘ってやつですよ
About Inspector Tsunemori's problems
with how she conducts herself...
常守朱監視官の問題行動について
I've submitted my reports
to you many times, Chief.
局長には何度も報告書を提出したはずです
Could you tell me
your thoughts about that?
その返答を　お聞かせいただけませんか
Oh, that doesn't
concern me much.
その件なら　大した問題ではない
Don't you think
it's dangerous to feel that way?
そう思っていらっしゃるなら　それは危険ではないでしょうか
Oh?
Her excessive hands-on approach,
過度な現場主義
distorted thinking due to her obsession
with uncertain matters,
確信のない事柄に執着する偏った思想
and her treatment of Enforcers...
執行官の扱い
These are all areas in which
Inspector Tsunemori has major problems.
それら全てにおいて
常守監視官は大きな問題を抱えています
And your point is?
だから　何だね
I just think that helping a colleague
come to their senses is part of my job.
同僚の目を覚まさせるのも　職務の一環と心得ています
Is that all you wanted to discuss?
用件はそれだけかな
No, there's one more thing.
いえ　もう一点
I am concerned about a troubling action
by Enforcer Sakuya Togane.
東金朔夜執行官の問題行動についてです
Are you talking about him
pointing his Dominator at an Inspector?
それは現場でドミネーターを監視官に向けたことを言ってるのかね
Yes.
はい
Just like you did,
君のように常守監視官の精神状態を　知りたかったのかもしれない
he might've wanted to know
Inspector Tsunemori's mental state...
...although it's true that wasn't
the best way to go about it.
手段としては少々問題はあるが
Inspector Tsunemori doesn't even
consider the risk posed by Enforcers,
潜在犯である執行官の危険性を考えもしない常守監視官では
who are latent criminals.
I have no doubt that this will eventually
turn into a major problem.
いずれ必ず大きな問題が生じます
When that happens,
could you...
そのときは　彼女の処遇について
...give a thought
to her treatment?
ぜひ　ご一考いただけないでしょうか
I'll think about it.
考えておこう
Please do not forget
what you just said.
今のお言葉　忘れないでください
Well then, excuse me.
失礼しました
That girl will be eaten alive.
あれは食われるな
This is...
これは…
A face transplant mask...?
顔そのものの移植パック？
This is strange.
おかしい
What did he need these for?
なぜ　こんなものを…
In order to maintain
Japan's vitality,
日本の活力を維持するためには　生活の安心と保障が不可欠である
we must ensure the security
and well-being of its people.
I have consistently
held this position
それが　私が初めて…
What a complete farce.
とんだ茶番だ
Hm?
ずっと訴え続けてきた持論です
...ever since I was first elected.
Japan has always been supported
by the vitality of its citizens...
いつの時代も国民の活力が社会を…
I've watched videos of all your speeches
over the past three years.
ここ３年分のあんたの演説　動画で全て見せてもらった
You're quite good
at giving speeches.
なかなか　うまいもんだ
It's vital for a politician
to be a good speaker, isn't it...?
演説の得手不得手は
やはり政治家にとって　生命線だろうな
One of the distinguishing
characteristics
代議士になった直後から　見られるあんたの特徴の一つは
you've had ever since
becoming a representative
is probably that mastery
of intonation that you have.
やはり巧みな抑揚のつけ方だろう
You purposely tone it down
when you're making important points,
聞かせるポイントで　あえてトーンを下げ
結果的に聴衆の注意力を高めている
and as a result,
it increases the audience's attention.
The balance is superb... No...
その加減が絶妙だ
いや　「だった」と言うべきか
...should I say, it was...
...in those videos of your
past speeches, at least.
少なくとも　過去の記録映像ではな
Your recent speeches
are no good
最近の演説はまるでなっちゃいない
though you do try hard
to imitate him.
よく似せちゃいるがな
Just...
あんた…
...who are you?
誰なんだ
Oh?
Is something wrong?
どうかしたか
The new "Hungry Chicken!"
is already out!
「ハングリーチキン」の新作　配信開始してんじゃん
Seriously?
Did they announce it?
マジかよ　告知してたっけ？
Hungry Chicken!
Oh, a video game...
ゲームか
I keep telling you to put that stuff away
while on duty, don't I?
仕事中は控えろと　いつも言ってるだろ
Come on, let me play a little.
Just a little.
ちょっとだけ　ちょっとだけ
Hungry Chicken!
Whoa...
What the hell?!
何だ？　いったい
Die, small fries.
死ね　ザーコ
I won't let you get away!
逃がすかよ
Inspector!
監視官
Looks like he was expecting us.
どうやら　われわれが来ることは　想定済みだったようです
You are a messenger.
You got arrested on purpose
お前は　メッセンジャーだ
わざと逮捕され　情報を与えて　公安を誘い込んだ
and lured in the MWPSB
by giving them information.
But what's your purpose?
だが　目的は何だ？
What are you trying to achieve
by roping in the MWPSB officers?
公安の人間を　おびき寄せて　何をさせたい？
Sending Shutdown Signal
It's not stopping!
止まらない
Why?!
何で？
What the hell's going on?!
何だ？　これは
Hungry Chicken!
What're you doing?!
Stop them already!
何をやっている　早く止めろ
It's not working!
The shutdown signal keeps getting rejected!
駄目です　停止信号拒否されます
Three Drones have just been
activated in Block F!
Ｆブロック　３体　新たに起動
All the Drones in Block G
and Block H are activated!
Ｇブロック　Ｈブロック　全機体起動しています
こんな…
Can't be...
I'm in luck!
ラッキー
Game on, MWPSB.
ゲームスタートだ　公安局
This is...
これは…
Door unlocked
by Inspector's request.
監視官権限により　ロック解除
What's... all this?
何？　これ…
All is calm, all is bright
All is calm All is bright
A whispering fallen angel
Sasayaku tenshi wa ochite
囁く天使は堕ちて
Gently devours you, body and soul
Yasashiku hamu wa anata no subete o
優しく食むわ　あなたの全てを
It's my guilty
You notice me
Kidzuku
気づく　目を見開いてる
With your eyes wide open,
Me o mihiraiteru
A faint blue as lifeless as concrete
Honoaoi konkuriito
仄青い混凝土
In a cold tone,
Tsumetaku watashi o
冷たく私を
Call my name and give me a kiss
And then hold me in the arms of the empty shell that is your body
Soshite dakishimete anata no inai sono karada de
そして抱きしめて
あなたのいないその体で
That soul that you've cast out
Hakidashita sono inochi wa
吐き出しその生命は
Has not yet completely vanished
Mada katachi o nokoshiteiru wa
まだ形を残しているわ　紅く
I glimpse a vivid red eternity
Akaku azayaka na eien ga miete
鮮やかな永遠が見えて
It starts singing right next to me
Tonari de sore wa utaidasu
隣でそれは歌いだすわ
What was I born for
Come on, love me
Nee watashi o aishite
ねえ　私を愛して
Because I won't let you go
Hanasanai kara
離さないから
Hello my name is
A world where humans' state of mind
and the tendency of their personalities can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed, these measured numbers used to judge people's souls
are commonly called 'Psycho-Pass.'
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations
that appear in the show are fictitious,
and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.